revzilla.com 2019-06-30

# Privacy Policy - RevZilla

Your Privacy Is Important To Us

RevZilla is committed to your privacy and the protection of your Personal Data. Personal Data is defined herein as any information that can be used to identify a particular individual under applicable data protection laws, including the General Data Protection Regulation (“GDPR”) (EU) (2016/679), California Consumer Privacy Act of 2018 etc. (collectively, “Data Protection Laws). This Privacy Statement describes our privacy practices as required by Data Protection Laws. This Privacy Statement applies where RevZilla is acting as a data Controller with respect to the Personal Data of our customers, partners, resellers, suppliers and website users; in other words, where we determine the purposes and means of the processing of Personal Data.

This privacy statement explains how we protect your personal information and data based on your use of our website, mobile apps, blogs, etc., as well as third party websites, mobile apps, and social media sites (“Sites”).

This Privacy Statement outlines how we collect, share, transfer, retain and protect your Personal Data and the rights you can exercise regarding your information. If you provide us with your Personal Data, or we obtain information about you from other sources, we treat your information according to this Privacy Statement.

Click on any of the topics below to learn more.

What Information Do We Collect About You?

The following describes the general categories of personal data that we may process, the purposes for which we may process the data, and the legal bases of the processing.

  * The following describes the general categories of Personal Data that we may process, the purposes for which we may process Personal Data, and the legal bases of the processing. In the case of Personal Data we did not obtain directly from you, we describe the source and specific categories of that data collected.

  * We may collect and process information related to your transactions with us.   These transactions include purchases of goods and services that you enter into with us and/or through our website or websites linked to our Site, via phone or email interactions with our employees, or retail locations (“Transaction Data”).  The Transaction Data may include your contact details (such as company, name, or phone number), and the transaction details.  The Transaction Data may be processed for the purpose of supplying the purchased goods and services and keeping proper records of those transactions. The legal basis for this processing is the performance of a contract between you and us and/or taking steps, at your request, to enter into such a contract and our legitimate interests in the proper administration of our website and business.  

  * We may collect and process data related to your account (“Account Data”).  The Account Data may include your name, title, postal and email address as well as payment information.  The source of the Account Data may be you or your employer when you are acting in a business capacity for your employer. The Account Data may be processed for the purposes of operating our website, providing our services, ensuring the security of our Sites and services, maintaining back-ups of our databases and communicating with you. The legal basis for this processing is our legitimate interests, namely the performance of a contract between you and RevZilla and/or taking steps, at your request, to enter into such a contract.  

  * We may collect and process information contained in any inquiry you submit to us regarding goods and services (“Inquiry Data”).  The legal basis for this processing is our legitimate interests, namely the performance of a contract between you and RevZilla and/or taking steps, at your request, to enter into such a contract.  

  * We may collect and process data about your use of our Sites and services and in our stores (“Usage Data”). The Usage Data may include your IP address, geographical location, browser type and version, operating system, referral source, length of visit, page views and website navigation paths, as well as information about the timing, frequency and pattern of your service use. The source of the Usage Data may be cookies, analytics tracking systems or other technologies.   This Usage Data may be processed for the purposes of analyzing your use of our Sites and services. The legal basis for this processing is consent.  See below for further details on “Cookies, Web Beacons and Other Tracking Technologies.”

  * We may collect process data about you to ensure security of your Personal Data and our IT systems.  The legal basis for this processing is our legitimate interests, namely the safe and secure:  (1) administration of our Sites, (2) use and storage of business information and, (3) communications with users and customers.  

  * We may collect and process information that you provide to us for the purpose of providing you with additional information on our goods and services, subscribing to our email notifications, and/or newsletters to keep you up-to-date on RevZilla products, events and news (“Notification Data”). The legal basis for this processing is your explicit consent, or your implicit consent if you are a customer.    
We may collect and process information contained in or relating to any communication that you send to us (“Correspondence Data”). The Correspondence Data may include the communication content and metadata associated with the communication.  Our Sites will generate the metadata associated with communications made using the specific Site contact forms. The Correspondence Data may be processed for the purposes of communicating with you and record-keeping. The legal basis for this processing is our legitimate interests, namely the proper administration of our Sites and business and communications with users and customers.

  * We may collect and process your Personal Data where necessary for the establishment, exercise, or defense of legal claims, whether in court proceedings or in an administrative or out-of-court procedure, an investigation, or other legal matter. The legal basis for this processing is our legitimate interests, namely the protection and assertion of our legal rights, your legal rights and the legal rights of others.

  * We may collect and process your Personal Data where necessary for the purposes of obtaining or maintaining insurance coverage, managing risks, or obtaining professional advice. The legal basis for this processing is our legitimate interests, namely the proper protection of our business against risks.

  * We may collect and process the personal information included in your personal profile on our Sites or in our stores (“Profile Data”). This Profile Data may include your name, address, telephone number, email address, motorcycle riding style, vehicles owned or of interest, gender, and date of birth, interests and hobbies including social network profiles. The Profile Data may be processed for the purposes of enabling and monitoring your use of our Sites and services. The legal basis for this processing is consent. We may collect and process information, including contact details in our stores or at events (name, postal address, email address, phone number)  that you provide to us for the purpose of providing you with additional information on our goods and services, subscribing to our email notifications, newsletters, catalogs, mailings to keep you up-to-date on products, events and news (“Notification Data”). The legal basis for this processing is your explicit consent or your implicit consent if you are a customer.

Where the processing of your Personal Data is based on your consent only, you have the right to withdraw this consent at any time.

Sources of Information We Collect About You

RevZilla receives information about you or your devices from the following sources:

  * When you, or someone on your behalf, provides information to us to:

    * Establish or maintain an account;

    * Make a purchase or receive a service;

    * Apply for employment at RevZilla;

    * Post comments to online communities;

    * Participate in a survey, marketing promotion, sweepstakes or contest; or

    * Connect with us via social media.

    * Receive email or postal mail, about updates to product, services or promotions

  * Through business partners, resellers and suppliers;

  * Our Sites, apps and email;

  * Through the use of automated means such as Cookies and similar technologies, and;

  * From other third parties, including, advertisers, data partners, marketing partners and publicly available sources such as social networks.

RevZilla, our service providers, and other third parties may collect the following information about you through automated means (such as Cookies):

  * IP address;

  * Browser type and language, access time, and referring website address;  

  * The pages you view within our Sites and other actions you take while visiting us;

  * We may collect information related to whether you've opened an e-mail or clicked on a link contained in an e-mail;

  * If you are referred to our Sites from another source (an advertising site, a blog, a social media site, etc.), we may collect data about you.  Also, we may provide a referring source with appropriate data (such as the amount of a purchase) to compute referral fees or other similar purposes;

  * We may conduct surveys and promotions that collect your information. Our surveys and promotions are voluntary and any information you provide may be collected, used, shared, disclosed, stored, transferred, and processed in accordance with this policy. Your participation in our surveys and promotions, and your submission of information, serves as your consent to these practices;

  * Some features of our Sites permit user generated content which may be made public or engage in other sharing. If you post content or otherwise participate in discussion forums or other social areas of our Sites, your participation (including the content you post, your name, and a link to your profile) may be shared across our Sites and in other public or private areas of the internet. For example, you may choose to submit a product review or participate in our Q&A section on product pages. If you choose to do so, we will ask for your email address and geographic location. If you submit a review, your geographic location will be visible to other users (your email address will be kept private). Also, any personally identifiable information that you submit as part of the review can be read or used by other visitors to the Sites. We are not responsible for any Personal Data that you choose to submit as part of your review. We believe you can post a helpful review or comment without disclosing any personal information.

Collecting information through automated means allows us to collect statistics about the usage and effectiveness of our Sites, personalize your experience on our Sites, and tailor our interactions with you. For details regarding the technologies we employ, see the section below regarding cookies, web beacons and similar technologies.

How We Use Your Information

We may use your information in various ways to serve you better as a customer and provide an improved online experience. The table provided below outlines how and why we use your Personal Data:

Info Category  
| How we use it  
| Why we use it  
  
---|---|---  
Name and Contact  
| Deliver your purchase  
| To fulfill our contract as retailers and send you moto stuff  

| Send you order updates through email and text  
| To fulfill our contract as retailers and send you order updates  

| Send you info on products and articles  
| To keep you up to date. This is only with your permission.  

| Fraud prevention and detection  
| To prevent and detect fraud against you and/or RevZilla  

| Show you ads while you're browsing the web  
| So you can see our latest products and deals. This is only with your permission.  

| Find out what you and other customers like  
| To ensure we're giving you what you want and to stay ahead of competition. This is only with your permission.  
  
Birthday  
| Fraud prevention and detection  
| To prevent and detect fraud against you and/or RevZilla  
  
Riding Style  
| Show and send you updates on the appropriate products  
| So you can see what you want to see faster. This is only with your permission.  
  
Gender  
| Show and send you updates on the appropriate products  
| So you can see what you want to see faster. This is only with your permission.  
  
Physical Traits  
| In the private version of your Account for Customer Service  
| So Customer Service can help find you the right gear  
  
Payment  
| Take payment and provide refunds  
| To fulfill our contract as retailers  

| Fraud prevention and detection  
| To prevent and detect fraud against you and/or RevZilla  
  
Order History and Saved Items  
| To sell you things  
| To fulfill our job as retailers / allow you to buy moto stuff  

| Provide customer service, support, and handle returns  
| To fulfill our job as retailers  

| Find out what you and other customers like  
| To ensure we're giving you what you want and to stay ahead of competition  
  
Contact History  
| Provide customer service and support  
| To fulfill our job as retailers / help you with all your moto needs  

| Train our staff  
| So we can provide the best customer service possible. This is only with your permission.  
  
Device and Usage  
| To improve our website and set default options  
| To give you the best shopping experience. This is only with your permission.  

| Protect our website  
| To prevent and detect fraud against you and/or RevZilla  
  
Info from Linked Accounts  
| So you can log into our website easily  
| To make it easier for you to use the website and purchase moto stuff  

| To provide product recommendations  
| So you can the our latest products and deals specific to your liking. This is only with your permission.  
  
Responses to Surveys, Competitions, and Promotions  
| Run surveys, competitions, or promotions  
| To fulfill our contract as retailers and provide you opportunities to win awesome stuff. This is only with your permission.  

RevZilla may use your personal information in the following ways:

  * Account Maintenance – We may use your information to identify you, ship products to you, contact you and provide billing services.
  * E-mail – If you choose to be contacted by email, we may use your email information to communicate questions, respond to inquiries, and distribute information about RevZilla and our products and services that may be of interest to you. You may choose not to receive marketing materials from us at any time by following the unsubscribe instructions included in the Email Marketing Preferences section below.
  * Transactions – If you request something from RevZilla, such as a product, service, callback, or marketing materials, we may use the information you provide to fulfill your request.  To help us complete your transaction, we may share information with others such as business partners, financial institutions, credit reference agencies, shipping companies, suppliers, resellers, or customs authorities.
  * Customer Feedback and Support – We may use your information to provide a mechanism for your feedback or to contact you regarding support for our products and services, including product updates or fixes.    
Personalizing your Experience on our Sites and Marketing Communications– We may use information we collect about you to provide a personalized experience on our Sites, emails and mailings such as providing you with content which you may be interested in, and to make our Sites easier for you to navigate.  
  * Aggregate/De-Identified Information - We may aggregate and/or de-identify your information so that such information can no longer be linked to you or your devices (Aggregate/De-Identified Information). We may use Aggregated/De-Identified Information for any purpose, including without limitation, research and marketing purposes.  We may also share aggregated data with any third parties, including advertisers, promotional partners, sponsors, event promoters, and/or others.
  * Combined Information - You consent that, for the purposes discussed in this Policy, we may combine the information that we collect with information that we receive from other sources, both online and offline, and use such combined information in accordance with this Policy.

International Data Transfers

RevZilla is a global business based in the United States.  We may process your information in, or transfer your information to, the United States, third parties in the United States, or other countries.   International transfers of your personal data to will be protected by appropriate safeguards, namely the use of Standard Contractual Clauses adopted or approved by the European Commission.  Our customers and the users of our Sites may be located anywhere in the world.  The privacy laws in some countries may not provide protections equivalent to those in your country of residence, and your government may or may not deem such privacy protections adequate.

Your Email and Mail Marketing Choices

If you have provided consent or you are an existing customer, we will send you marketing messages via email and/or mail to keep you up to speed on all things RevZilla.

You can stop receiving marketing messages from us at any time through the following methods:

  * Through your customer account settings within “My Account”

  * By clicking on the ‘unsubscribe’ link in any email communication

  * By contacting one of Geek team members at cs@revzilla.com

Once one of these methods is completed, we will update your profile to ensure that you don’t receive further marketing messages.

RevZilla is made up of a complex web of many inter-connecting services and it may take up to 60 days for all our systems to reflect these updates. We ask for your understanding that during this period you may still get messages from us while your request is being processed.

Please note that the discontinuation of marketing messages will not stop any service communications such as order updates.

Security

There is no perfect security. We have implemented physical, technical, and administrative measures to help prevent unauthorized access, use and disclosure of your Personal Data, but we cannot promise that these measures will work. You are responsible for maintaining the secrecy of any credentials that can be used to access your RevZilla account. You should report suspected unauthorized activity to us immediately. For more details, see our Security Information Page.

Third Party Links

We may collect your information from third parties. This includes you logging in through a third party site such as Facebook, Google, Snapchat, Instagram, LinkedIn, Twitter, etc. We may also disclose information collected from third parties to customize ads and to manage and facilitate messaging on third party sites. We do not control the privacy practices of third parties. We encourage you to review the privacy policies of third party sites for more information regarding their applicable privacy practices.

Data Retention

We will keep your personal data while we are providing our products and services to you. Thereafter, we will keep your personal data for one of these reasons: (a) to respond to any questions, complaints or claims made by you or on your behalf; (b) to show that we treated you fairly; (c) to keep records required by law; (d) for communication with one of our Geek team members, and; (e) to provide support-related reporting and trend analysis.

We will not retain your data for longer than necessary for the purposes for which it was collected as set out in this privacy notice. In determining data retention periods, we take into consideration local laws, contractual obligations, our reasonable business requirements, and your expectations and requirements.  When it is no longer necessary to retain your personal data, we will securely delete or anonymize it.

Advertising

We participate in online advertising to keep our customers up to speed on product offerings, site and in-store promotions, and associated content. Like many companies, we utilize targeted RevZilla banners and ads and may display these to you when you are on other websites and apps. We do this using a variety of digital marketing networks and ad exchanges in addition to using a range of advertising technologies like web beacons, pixels, ad tags, cookies, and mobile identifiers, as well as specific services offered by some sites and social networks.

The banners and ads that you may see displayed will be based on information we hold about you, or your previous use of RevZilla Sites.  This may include your RevZilla search history, the content you read on RevZilla or on RevZilla banners or ads you have previously clicked on.

Cookies, Web Beacons and Other Technologies

Like many sites, our Sites employ cookies and web beacons to speed your navigation of the Site, recognize you and your access privileges, and track your Site usage.

  * Cookies are small pieces of information that are stored as text files by your Internet browser on your computer’s hard drive. Most Internet browsers are initially set to accept cookies. You can set your browser to refuse cookies from websites or to remove cookies from your hard drive, but if you do, you will not be able to access or use portions of the site.  
Web beacons assist in delivering cookies and help us determine whether a web page on the site has been viewed and, if so, how many times. For example, any electronic image on the Sites, such as a product image, can function as a web beacon.  
Revzilla utilizes several Google Analytics products, including remarketing with Google Analytics, Google Display Network Impression Reporting and Google Analytics Demographics and Interest Reporting. Visitors may opt out of these features through Ads Settings, Ad Settings for mobile apps, Google's opt-out browser, or other available methods.

If you would like to opt-out of cookies generally, visit www.aboutcookies.org or www.allaboutcookies.org for further information. These websites also tell you how to set your browser not to accept cookies and how to remove cookies from your browser. However, in a few cases, some of the features on our Sites may not function as a result.

Compliance with Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act

Protecting the privacy of the anyone under the age of 13 is especially important. For that reason, we never collect or maintain information on our Sites from those we actually know are under the age of 13, and no part of our Sites are structured to engage anyone under the age of 13.

If RevZilla learns that it possesses information from a child under the age of 13, we delete that information from our systems. If you are a parent or guardian and are aware that your child has provided us with personal information, please contact us so that we will be able to take the necessary actions to delete such data.

Do Not Track

RevZilla does not track its customers over time and across third party websites to provide targeted advertising and therefore does not respond to Do Not Track (DNT) signals. However, some third party sites do keep track of your browsing activities when they serve you content, which enables them to tailor what they present to you. If you are visiting such sites, you may be able to set the DNT signal on your browser so that third parties (particularly advertisers) know you do not want to be tracked.

Using Mobile and Other Devices

RevZilla or third parties that we have engaged, may collect and store unique identifiers matched to your mobile device in order to deliver customized ads or content while you use our Sites, navigate the internet, or to identify you in a unique manner across devices or browsers. In order to customize these ads or content, we, or third parties, may collect your information, e.g., your email address, or data passively collected from you such as your device identifier or IP address.

By adjusting the privacy and security settings on your device, you can manage how your mobile device and mobile browser share information, as well as how your mobile browser handles Cookies and other tracking identifiers. Please refer to instructions provided by your mobile service provider or the manufacturer of your device to learn how to adjust your settings.

Text Messaging and Alerts – Opting In and Out

Our mobile Sites may give you the choice to opt-in to receiving text messages and alerts on the mobile phone number(s) you have shared with us. Once you have opted-in, we may send you text messages (i) regarding your account; (ii) to investigate or prevent fraud; and (iii) to alert you in the event of an emergency. We may send you text messages and alerts using autodialed technology. We will not contact you via text messages or alerts for marketing purposes without your prior express written consent. You do not have to opt-in to text messages and alerts to use our Sites. If you opt-in, standard text messaging charges may apply. For more information regarding our text messaging and alerts, please contact us at webmaster@revzilla.com. You may choose to opt-out from our text messages and alerts at any time using any reasonable means. To directly opt-out send us a text message from your mobile phone with the word STOP, STOP ALL, END, QUIT, CANCEL or UNSUBSCRIBE and we will unsubscribe you from text communications. Once you opt-out, you will not receive any additional text messages via your mobile phone. Please keep in mind that if you opt-out of receiving text messages and alerts we may not be able to contact you with important messages regarding your account. However, if there is an emergency or account question, we will make every attempt to contact you in other ways such as email or on a landline phone.

Your Rights

You can inquire about your personal information, ask the following questions, or take the following actions by contacting us via email at [privacy@revzilla.com](mailto:privacy@revzilla.com) or via the address or phone number below to:

By adjusting the privacy and security settings on your device, you can manage how your mobile device and mobile browser share information, as well as how your mobile browser handles Cookies and other tracking identifiers. Please refer to instructions provided by your mobile service provider or the manufacturer of your device to learn how to adjust your settings.

  * See what information we have about you if any,

  * Change/correct any information we have about you,

  * Have us delete any information we have about you,

  * Express any concerns you have about our use of your information.

Under certain conditions, you may have the right to:

  * access your personal data;

  * rectification of your personal data;

  * erasure of your personal data;

  * restrict processing of your personal data;

  * portability of your personal data;

  * unsubscribe from marketing material at any time;

  * withdraw your consent to certain processing activities.

  * request information on the types of organization your information has been shared with for co-marketing purposes.

For more information on the full extent of your rights or to exercise your rights, please contact our Data Protection Officer as described below.

Your California Privacy Rights

Subject to certain limits under California Civil Code if you are a California resident, you may ask us to provide you with a list of certain categories of personal information (as defined in the Civil Code) that we have disclosed to third parties for their direct marketing purposes during the immediately preceding calendar year and the identity of the third parties that received personal information from us for their direct marketing purposes during that calendar year. To make such a request, please contact us at [privacy@revzilla.com](mailto:privacy@revzilla.com).

Privacy Statement Updates

If we change or update this Privacy Policy, we will post changes and updates on our Site so that you will always be aware of what information we collect, use and disclose. When significant changes are made to our Privacy Policy or processes, we will send an updated notice via email to inform you. If you have any questions about the Privacy Policy, please contact us using the information above.

What’s New?

Effective March 1, 2019, we changed our Privacy Statement to clarify the types of information we collect about you, the ways we collect your information and how we may use and share your information.

Here is a summary of the changes:

  * We now use the term “Sites” to describe our website, mobile apps, blogs, etc. as well as third party websites, mobile apps, social media sites, and physical store locations.

  * We clarify the types of information we collect about you and the ways we collect this data (we collect information in many ways, including from third party sites, social media sites, and advertising networks).

  * We describe how we share and use your information, whether collected by our Sites, or other websites, including social media sites and advertising partners, for the purposes of ad targeting, remarketing and customizing ad content.

  * We notify users that we may share data with motorcycle-related co-marketing partners.

  * We describe our use of email communications and text messaging and how to opt out and/or control these communications.

  * We notify users as to their rights under the California law.

  * We clarify that your information may be transferred across international borders for processing and other uses.

  * We clarify how we share your information with our suppliers, third party vendors and referring Sites.

  * We describe our use of Cookies and other tracking technologies. We detail how these technologies work and how we may use and share the information we collect from these technologies.

  * We include information on Do Not Track signals.

  * We clarify that this policy covers data that we collect in stores.

  * We clarify the use of postal mail and your ability to opt out of those communications.
